Resurrection
Ryuuzaki, let me go.
竜崎、私に行かせてくれ
Chief, I'm coming too!
局長、私も行きます
Understood.
わかりました
Remember that you're dealing with Kira.
相手はキラです
Under no circumstances should you let him see your face, and exercise extreme caution while restraining him.
絶対顔を見せず、細心の注意を払って捕まえてください
Watari, if Higuchi makes even one suspicious move...
ワタリ
火口が少しでも妙な動きをしたら…
I understand. I'll immobilize him without actually killing him.
はい
殺さぬ程度に動きを止めます
Aizawa, did you bring something to obscure your face with?
相沢
顔を隠す物の用意はあるか？
Yes.
はい
Back us up.
援護をしてくれ
Understood! Thank you very much, Chief!
はい！
ありがとうございます、局長
Higuchi, put both hands up and step out of the car!
火口、両手を挙げ、車から降りなさい
Higuchi has been secured.
火口を確保した
Mogi-san, as we planned, place the transceiver on him.
模木さん、手筈通り、火口にレシーバーを
receiver
Yes!
はい
Higuchi, how were you killing people? Answer me!
火口
どうやって殺人をしてきた、言うんだ
Higuchi, how were you killing people? Answer me!
If you don't, we'll make you confess using any means at our disposal.
言わなければ、どんな手を使ってでも言わせます
It's a notebook...
…ノートだ
A notebook?
ノート？
You probably won't believe me, but if you write the name of a person whose face you know in that notebook, that person will die.
信じられないだろうが…
顔を知っている人間の名前を書くと、
書かれた人間が死ぬノートだ…
A notebook...
ノート…
Yagami-san?
夜神さん
Yes... I've found it in his bag.
ああ
火口のバックの中にあった
It's true there are names written here, but there's nothing unusual about this note--
確かに人の名前は書いてあるが…
格別変わったノートでは…
What's wrong, Yagami-san?
どうしました？夜神さん
M-Monster!!
ば…化物…
Calm down. Yagami-san, you aren't carrying a gun at the moment.
落ち着いてください
夜神さんは今拳銃を所持していません
Yes... yes, that's right.
そ…そうだった…
Are you okay, Chief?
大丈夫ですか？局長
M-Mogi! Can't you see that thing?!
も…模木、あれが見えないのか…
Chief, you're very tired at the moment--
局長…疲れてるんですよ
What's happening, Mogi-san?!
どうしたんだ、模木さん！
A-Ah... I-It looks like only those who've touched this notebook can see this... this monster!
こ、これは…
どうやらノートを触った者でしか見えないらしい
A-Ah... I-It looks like only those who've touched this notebook can see this... this monster!
ば…化物が…
Please bring that notebook to the helicopter.
そのノートをヘリに持ってきてください
R-Right...
…はい
What can you possibly be planning, Yagami Light?
一体どうする気だ、夜神月
By touching a Death Note that you previously owned, all your memories associated with it will be recovered.
お前がノートを再び手にすれば
所有権があった時のデスノートの記憶全てが…甦る事にはなるが
However...
しかし…
Ryuuzaki, here it is.
竜崎、これです
I-It's a Shinigami... they really do... exist...
死神…ですね
本当に…いた…んですね…
I-It's a Shinigami... they really do... exist...
Yagami Light...
Notebook...
ノート…
青山でノートを見せる…
Showed each other our notebooks in Aoyama...
Love at first sight...
一目惚れしたのに
The second Kira...
Ryuuzaki, give me the notebook!
竜崎、僕にもノートを…
Kira's method of killing...
殺人の手段…キラ、第二…
Kira... the second Kira...
Two notebooks...
二冊…
More than one notebook exists.
ノートは二冊以上存在している…
It's not over yet...
まだ終わってない…
うぐああああああああああーーー
I am L...
L です
私はL です…
A-Are you okay? Anyone would be petrified if they saw that monster.
だ、大丈夫…ですか？
誰だってあんな化物には驚く
Ryuuzaki?
竜崎
Yes?
はい
Firstly, we've got to compare the names written here against the list of victims.
まずはここに書かれている人達と…
犠牲者の名前を照合してみるよ
Erm... yes... I suppose you're right...
え？…はい
まぁ…そうですね
I've won.
勝った…
Just as planned!
計画通り…
I'm relinquishing all ownership of this notebook.
このノートの所有権を…放棄する
The ownership of this notebook now returns to Rem. Correct?
これでこのノートの所有権はレムに戻った…そうだな
Correct. Your point being?
そうだ、しつこいぞ
Okay, now give that notebook to Ryuk.
じゃあ、そのノートをリュークにあげてくれ
え？
Fine.
いいだろう
The owner of this notebook is now Ryuk.
これでそのノートの所有権はリュークになった
Ryuk, next, I want you to drop that notebook here, onto the ground of the human world.
リューク
それをまた人間界の地に、今そこに落としてくれ
Huh? Well, guess it's okay...
え？…まあ、いいけど
And so the ownership returns to me.
これでまた所有権は僕だ
おいおい
So the ownership has gone round in a circle; nothing has changed.
一周しただけで何も変わってないだろ
Maybe...
ああ、そうかもな
But there'll be a time when this will be of use.
しかしこれが必ず役に立つ時が来る…
And the first notebook that I received from Ryuk...
そして僕が最初にもらったこのノート…
I'm giving it back to you, and I want you to give it to Rem.
今度はこれをリュークに返すから、レムにあげてくれ
え？
Here.
はい
Rem, I'll need you to pass that to someone who has a reasonably high status, yet remains greedy for success.
レム
それをある程度の地位があり、
出世欲が強く、その為に使うであろう人間に渡すんだ
Someone who'll undoubtedly use the notebook to further those goals.
Doing this will guarantee Misa's release from imprisonment.
それをすれば必ず海砂は…今の監禁から解放される
If she still hasn't been released after several years, kill me. How's that?
何年たっても解放されない様なら僕を殺せ
それでそうだ？
Yagami Light, what are you planning?
夜神月、何を考えている
This is all to save Misa. Trust me.
海砂を助ける為だ
僕を信用しろ
Understood... if this will help Misa, I'll do as you say.
わかった
海砂が助かるなら、言う通りにしてやろう
Next, I'll manipulate the situation so, like Misa, I'll be detained and under 24-hour surveillance.
僕はこのあと、海砂のように監禁され
２４時間監視状態になるよう仕向ける
While in detention, I'll relinquish all ownership of the Death Note and it'll erase any associated memories I've got.
その状態でノートの所有権を放棄し
デスノートに関する記憶を全て無くす…
During that time, the judging of criminals will recommence, and if that continues, at some stage, Ryuuzaki will be forced to release us both.
その間に犯罪者裁きは復活し
それが続けば…
竜崎はいつかは二人を解放せざるをえなくなる
And then, with my memories gone, I'm sure I'll attempt to catch Kira.
そして記憶を失った僕は…
必ずキラを捕まえようとするだろう
It's just the type of person I am.
僕はそういう人間だ
So, you plan to find the person Rem gives the notebook to before L can, and reclaim the notebook?
そして L より先に、
レムがノートを渡す奴を捕まえ、ノートを奪うってことか…
Exactly. And I'll kill whoever has ownership of it.
そうだ
そしてその時のノートの持ち主を殺す…
But there is one problem:
しかし問題がひとつある
If you hold no ownership over that Death Note, your memories will only return as long as you're physically touching it.
所有権を持っていなければ、
記憶が戻るのはノートに触っている間だけだ
The moment you let go, all your memories will be erased once more.
手を放せばまた、全ての記憶がなくなる
I need to kill Higuchi without letting go of this notebook.
このノートから手を放さないまま…火口を殺す
That way, the ownership will pass to me, and my memories won't disappear.
そうすれば所有権は僕に移り、記憶は消えない…
If I pull this four times with less than a second between each...
ここを一秒以上の間隔を開けずに四回引く…
Success! I knew I'd be wearing this at the time.
よし！
やはり僕はこの時計をつけていた…
Old habits die hard.
習慣ってものは変わらない
Yagami-san, please escort Higuchi to the car.
夜神さん、火口を車へお願いします
O-Okay... understood.
あ…ああ…、わかった
This notebook... if analyzed scientifically, I wonder if we'd discover anything.
このノート
ん？
This notebook... if analyzed scientifically, I wonder if we'd discover anything.
科学分析とかしたら、何か出るだろうか
Yagami-kun, that's not like you. That thing is beyond science.
夜神君らしくないですね
科学なんて超えてますよ、それは
はは…それもそうだ
I guess you're right.
This is the longest 40 seconds of my life...
一生のうちで、一番長い 40 秒だ…
Higuchi! Ryuuzaki! Higuchi is...
火口…!?
竜崎、火口が…
Higuchi! Ryuuzaki! Higuchi is...
What?! What's going on?!
…何だ!?どうしたんだ？
Hey, Higuchi?!
…おい、火口
な…何をやっているんだ、父さん
What are you doing, father?! If Higuchi dies now...
もしここで、火口に死なれでもしたら…
T-This isn't possible... but I think he's...
ま…まさか…
いや、しかし…これはもう…
Yeah, he's dead.
ああ…死んでるさ
The next, Ryuuzaki... will be you.
次は竜崎…
おまえだ
"How to use"...
HOW TO USE
"The human whose name is written in this note shall die."
このノートに名前を書かれた人間は…死ぬ
"This note will not take effect unless the writer has the person's face in their mind when they write his/her name."
書かれる人物の顔が頭に入っていないと効果はない
故に、同姓同名の人物に、一遍に効果は得られない
"Therefore, people sharing the same name will not be affected."
"If the cause of death is written within 40 seconds of writing the person's name, it will happen as it is written."
名前のあとに人間界単位で… 40 秒以内に死因を書くと
その通りになる
"If the cause of death is not specified, by default, the person will die of a heart attack."
死因を書かなければ…全ては心臓麻痺になる
"Should a cause of death be specified, a further 6 minutes and 40 seconds are granted to write any further details."
死因を書くとさらに 6 分 40 秒…
詳しい死の状況を記載する時間が与えられる
Furthermore, in the "How to use"-section at the back, it states:
さらに、裏表紙の方の… HOW TO USE
"If you make this note unusable by tearing it up or burning it, all the humans who have touched the note till then will die."
このノートを刻む役などして使えなくするとは
それまでにノートに触れた全ての人間が死ぬ…
What?! Is that true, Aizawa-san?
えっ？
ほ…本当ですか、相沢さん
ああ、そう書いてある
Yup, it's written right here.
There's no doubt that while that rule exists, they won't destroy the notebook, and there's no danger of me losing my memory.
そう
こういう掟があれば、父さん達にノートを処分され
Aw.. that's just shit... why didn't you tell me this earlier?
そんな～先に言ってくださいよ
だって知らないでしょ
僕の記憶がなくなる事もない…
Rem, I won't get in trouble with the old man for writing in fake rules, will I?
レム
ここに嘘のルール書いても、大王に怒られるわけないよな
じじい
No, there are no rules regarding that.
ああ、そんな掟はない
Alright then. But Light, I'm counting on you for more apples.
いいだろう
ライト、またリンゴ頼むぜ
Alright then. But Light, I'm counting on you for more apples.
Maybe I shouldn't have said "I want to see the Shinigami too", and touched that...
ああ…
「僕も死神見たい」なんて触らなければよかったかな
If you hadn't, you'd be the only one in the investigation not knowing what's going on.
それでは、どう捜査になっているか、松田だけがわからなくなる
いっ？
Is that what you want?
それでもいいのか？
いえ…僕も皆と同じ立場で捜査したいです、はい
N-No, I want to be on the same level as everyone else in this investigation. Really!
And this final sentence...
そして…この最後の一文
"If the person using the note fails to continuously write names of people to be killed within 13 days of each other, then the user will die."
このノートに名前を書き込んだ人間は…
もっとも新しく名前を書いた時から、
13 日以内に次の名前を書き込み、人を殺し続けなければ…
自分が死ぬ
Oh! This means that both Light-kun and Misa-Misa are completely cleared!
えっ？ってことは…
これで月君もミサミサも、完全に白ってことですね？
ああ、確かに
It's true.
Light-kun and Amane were imprisoned for over 50 days, and even now are under surveillance. If either were Kira, they'd no longer be alive.
５０日以上監禁され、今も監視下にある月君と弥
二人がキラなら、今生きているはずがない
That's great news, isn't it, Chief?
よかったですね、局長
Yes.
ああ…
Rem-san... wasn't it? The white person over there.
レムさん…
でしたね、そこの白い方
R-Ryuuzaki, that's rude! You can't go around calling them "white".
り、竜崎…
失礼じゃないですか、白いとか…
Correct.
そうだが
There are other Death Notes in the human world, aren't there?
ノートは他にも人間界にありますね
Not sure. Maybe there are, maybe there aren't.
さあ？
あるかもしれないし、ないかもしれない
If other notebooks did exist, would the rules be the same for all of them?
もし他のノートが存在していたら…
全てのノートのルールは同じですか？
If other notebooks did exist, would the rules be the same for all of them?
It's no use, Ryuuzaki. There's no way that Rem will let you cast doubt upon these rules.
無駄だよ竜崎
このルールーはレムから絶対崩せない
Yes, they'd be the same.
ああ、同じだ
There are many notebooks within the world of Shinigami, but the rules are all the same.
ノートは死神界にいくらでもあるが、ルールは全て同じだ
Those notebooks under human possession also share a common set of rules.
人間に持たせた時のルールもだ
Ryuuzaki, the suspicions surrounding Light-kun and Amane have been cleared.
竜崎
月君と弥の疑いは晴れた
It's time to end their surveillance.
二人の監視は終わりだ
He's right, it's obvious.
そうですよ
もう明白ですよ
You're right...
…そうですね
I understand.
わかりました
I apologize for everything up until now.
今まで申し訳ありませんでした
I'm so glad.
よかった…
ああ
Yeah.
But the case is still far from solved.
しかしまだ、この事件は完全解決とは言えない
Although these handcuffs will be removed, I'll continue to investigate from here, if that's alright.
手錠は外させてもらうが、ここで捜査を続けていいな？
Yes.
はい
Now Misa and I are 100% clear of suspicion.
これで僕と海砂は…１００％白だ
Rules written by a Shinigami in a Death Note... you'd have to believe them.
死のノートに、死神によって書かれたルール…
これが信じるしかない
Thanks to the fake rules I created, Ryuuzaki has nowhere to go from here.
僕の作った嘘のルールによって…竜崎は手立てを失った
Understand this Ryuuzaki: in any world, rules are something that are made by the gods.
いいか竜崎
ルールとはいつの世界も…神とされる者によって作られる物だ
Understand this Ryuuzaki: in any world, rules are something that are made by the gods.
You will bow down to the rules I've created.
お前は僕の作ったルールに平伏し、
新世界の神に逆らおうとした罪で…
You tried to oppose me, the new god of this world, and for your transgression, you will die.
死ぬんだ
Light! Promise me that you'll text me every single day.
ライト…
絶対毎日メールしてね…
うううう…
I can't believe that I finally have to part with Misa-Misa...
ついにミサミサとももう別れか…
おい、松田
Oi, Matsuda, leave them alone.
二人きりに！
See ya, Misa-Misa!
じゃあね、ミサミサ
Hey!
おい！
Even if we can be seen on the security cameras, from this angle, they shouldn't be able to see my mouth.
この角度なら、
監視カメラに見られていたとしても、僕の口は映らない
Misa, when you're certain that no one else is around, I want you to go to the place I'm about to tell you and dig up something for me.
海砂
今から言う場所に埋めてある物を、
絶対誰も見ていない時に…一人で掘り出してくれ
Light! Your memories have returned!
ライト…記憶戻ったのね
大丈夫、海砂うまくやるよ
Don't worry, Misa will do good!
Light, I remember! Everything that happened back when I was using this notebook... You must have buried this notebook so that I'd remember too!
ライト、思い出したよ
このノートを使っていた時の事…
海砂も思い出せるように、こっちのノートを埋めてくれたんだね
Light, I remember! Everything that happened back when I was using this notebook... You must have buried this notebook so that I'd remember too!
Misa, if you're reading this, it's likely that your memory has been restored.
海砂
君はこの手紙を読み頃には、全てを思い出しているはずだ
A letter from Light!
ライトからの手紙…
Do you remember a friend of mine, from Todai University, who introduced himself as "Ryuuga Hideki"?
東応大学で、流河旱樹と名乗った…僕の友人を覚えているか？
I want you to write his real name in this notebook and bury him.
彼の本名をノートに書き、葬って欲しい…
そしてこの手紙はすぐに燃やし、
ノートも数ページだけを隠し持ち
Then, as soon as possible, burn this letter.
Take only a few pages from the notebook, and re-bury the notebook itself.
ノート自体が埋めておくように…
The next time you see me, touch me with a piece of paper from this notebook as naturally as you can.
それと次に僕に会った時、
ノートの切れ端を自然に触れさせてくれ
If you can obey me in all this... I'll love you, forever.
これに従ってくれたら、僕は弥海砂を…
________________________...love you, forever!
一生愛す
Yay!
やった
I see. This is all Light's plan.
そうか、これがライトの計画
For me to obtain this notebook and regain my memory... and kill Ryuuga Hideki... Ryuuzaki...
海砂にこのノートを持たせ、記憶を戻し
流河旱樹…竜崎を殺す
For me to obtain this notebook and regain my memory... and kill Ryuuga Hideki... Ryuuzaki...
This should remove another obstacle for Light, and I'll have helped him!
これでライトの障害がひとつ消え、海砂はライトの力になれて…
ダメだよ…ライト
It's no good, Light. I can't remember his name.
名前なんて覚えてないよ…
I used to see tens, hundreds of names and lifespans every day...
一日何十人、何百人の人の名前と寿命が見えてたんだもん…
あーーー!!どうやっても思い出せない
There's no way I can remember! Stupid Misa!
海砂の馬鹿ーー
Finally! I'm back!
やっとこっちに戻ってくれた
Ryuk! It's so good to see you again!
リューク！
久しぶり、元気だった？
How have you been?
Erm, sorry but... being male and all that... that kinda makes me blush.
悪いが…
一応オレもオス、照れる
Erm, sorry but... being male and all that... that kinda makes me blush.
あははは…
あっ、そうだ
Oh, yeah!
Here you are!
はい
Light told me to bring it along.
ライトが持ってけって
Is it that good?
そんなにおいしい？
ああ
Yeah. Apples in the human world are... how d'ya say it? "Juicy"?
人間界のリンゴはジューシー…って言うの？
とにかくうまい
In any case, they're damned good.
You wanna try eating one?
海砂も食ってみる？
Huh?
It's an apple from the world of Shinigami.
死神界のリンゴだ
おいしくなさそう…
Doesn't look very tasty...
Take a bite.
まぁまぁ、一口
Oh, yeah, Ryuk. I want to trade eyes with you.
あと、そうだリューク
あたしと目の取引して
砂
Sand!!
You wanna make a deal, huh?
取引か？
You realize that you've already made a deal with Rem once, right?
わかってるのか
おまえ一度レムと取引してるんだぞ
Your remaining lifespan has already been halved once; you sure you wanna do it again?
半分にした残りの寿命を、また半分にしていいんだな
まぁ、それは仕方ないよ
It can't be helped I guess.
I've completely forgotten the one name that I needed to remember.
あたし覚えてなくちゃいけない
名前すっかりと忘れてしちゃってさ
Light will be mad at me unless I go and find it out again.
迎えみてくんないとライトに怒られちゃうもん
Well, that's fine by me.
まあ、オレはいいけど…
It's Misa-Misa!
あっ、ミサミサだ
Poor thing. We can't switch our cell phones on in here, so Misa-Misa has to come all the way here, just to see Light-kun.
可哀想に、ここじゃ携帯の電源も入れられないから
ミサミサの方から訪ねて来るしかないんだ
Light, hurry up and go see her.
月、早く行ってあげなさい
You shouldn't keep a lady waiting.
女性を待たすものではない
ああ
Sure.
Ryuk! Why is he with Misa?!
リューク…
何故海砂に憑いている…
Ryuk! Why is he with Misa?!
Misa's lifespan has halved again!
海砂の寿命がさらに半分に減っている…
Surely she didn't trade eyes with Ryuk?!
まさか…リュークと目の取引を…
Light.
ライト
Long time no see, Ryuk.
久し振りだな、リューク
L-Light, I'm so sorry. I can't remember Ryuuga Hideki's name, no matter how hard I try!
ラ…ライト、ごめん
流河旱樹の名前覚えてない…どうしても思い出せない
L-Light, I'm so sorry. I can't remember Ryuuga Hideki's name, no matter how hard I try!
I see...
そうか…残念だな
Well, that's a shame...
B-But I traded eyes with Ryuk!
で…でも、リュークと目の取引したから…
It's all going according to plan, huh?
全ては計算か…
You idiot! That means your lifespan has...
馬鹿…そんなことしたら、寿命が…
It doesn't matter. I want to help you!
ううん、いいの
ライトの役に立ちたい…
Misa, I want to be with you in an ideal world for as long as possible.
海砂
今の僕は、君と長く理想の世界で生きたい…
That's the way I feel, right now.
そういう気持ちなんだ
Light! I'm so happy!
ライト、嬉しい…
Misa, let's build a new world together... a world without criminals, filled only with kind-hearted people.
海砂
二人で犯罪のない、
優しい人間だけの…新しい世界を創っていこう
Misa, let's build a new world together... a world without criminals, filled only with kind-hearted people.
うん
To be continued
…さよなら